hey everybody welcome to this a1 english
listening practice video you can use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start remember to download the listening
time podcast and remember that you'll
receive my advanced podcast if you
become a listening time family member
okay today we're gonna talk about
retirement this is an interesting topic
because retirement is different around
the world so what is retirement when you
retire it means that you stop working
you finish your career so first let's
talk about the retirement age in the u.s
the retirement age is 66 or 67
it depends on when you were born however
this age might change in the future
when you turn 66 or 67 years old you can
stop working and get money from the
government in the u.s this is called
social security the retirement age is
different in different countries
but i think that it's usually 60
something in most countries what's the
retirement age in your country in the
u.s the social security money that
people receive isn't enough for most
people life is expensive in the u.s so
people often save money or invest so
they can retire i think in most
countries it's the same the money that
the government gives you when you retire
isn't a lot this means that people need
to plan for retirement
so let's talk about some ways to have
more money when you retire
one thing you can do is save money you
can save a little money each month and
this amount will grow as time goes by
you should start saving when you're
young if you start saving when you're 60
you probably won't save a lot of money
before you retire and sometimes saving
money isn't enough
over time there's always inflation
inflation is when your currency loses
value
so if there's a lot of inflation then
your savings lose value too this is why
some people prefer to invest money
there are many different ways to invest
money
you can invest in a retirement plan the
stock market
cryptocurrency gold silver real estate
and other things if you invest your
money well then you can make more money
in the future this can help you retire
one other important investment is
investing in your children if you have
children then you should invest a lot of
time money energy and love into them
if you do this then your children will
probably help you when you're older it's
much easier to retire when your children
love you and want to help you out now
let's talk about what people do when
they retire in the u.s there are many
popular activities for retired people
one common activity is golf if you go to
a golf course in the u.s you'll see many
retirees
another thing that many retired people
do is travel when people don't have to
work they have a lot of time to go
places
many people dream of retiring and
traveling around the world
and one last activity that many retired
people do is help take care of their
grandchildren if they have grandchildren
this is a very important activity for
many people grandparents love spending
time with their grandchildren and
parents appreciate the help
and actually some people never retire
some people continue working their whole
life they might do this because they
need the money or they might just love
working how about you do you want to
retire in the future or do you want to
continue working when you're old ok
that's all for today
remember to download my free listening
time podcast and if you want my advanced
podcast then become a listening time
family member at patreon.com
listeningtime also subscribe to the
channel click on the bell and follow us
on instagram i'll see you next time
[Music]